i'll go ahead and show you where they
uh...
heated
here at the current age
front page travel
their knowledge that there is
distracting you
down here on the bottom line
as opening
that that will take you directly to the
teachings
blankets you closer
o'connor and cheat sheet
yelling at home
inside there
there's the wikipedia chichi
every time you know at that link should
be at the bottom
and if you haven't done it
you can always rather have it in midtown
you can always do right-click
and select open in new window
and that sometimes such a cat
collecting it had to displays are really
white wine
via a ghetto if russia really try to
have a right to remember stuff
there
as long as tiny laurel stays in the
evenings within your life
the only trouble is if you move a pager
tiny lyle
that plus the political spot so doesn't
follow a document points into space
working toward with
we have what's called in that
network alias where all of our calcs
always machines come through and look
like they come from one could hear going
out to the internet
so were paying a price for
for doing that
because i think for all the same
personal centered here
and so it being searched thirty people
on piracy channel
from the same here
so you david
transfers
is actually more certain
yes just over the search for a fetus to
attach
so if you would
joy would if we need to set up our own
whiskey
server here
staked rounds of free now
that's attached to enjoy
tools
sold sold to
attached
piracy
dot net
so you touch versus
alia complain
and then you if you are
joins
compounds
perhaps character and a
u_n_ age
research
uh... because you're inside its economy
should be able as remote desktop from
these machines directly to your desktop
is erica's anyway still waiting to
connect and one of the couple
checking on the phone
here are your first name for a year
you need to memorize that
important
it'll be a lot of fish names
throughout the gas was fish is yours
know that between
yet some of them are insurmountable fish
names
if you guys can't make it piracy champ
today
look over your neighbors and if you have
a question
after they were taken in for you
i will try to have a nice easter setup
inside
firewall them we won't have this kind of
issue with
let's go ahead and get started because
please give me a short day
item number three is that i have to run
over to james hall if you want to go
t_v_ talk it yet again
and giving me brown bag seminar and
james hall
pure science department and i'll be
talking about paleomagnetics insert acre
feet
less about the repeaters and a lot more
about geology geophysics
but today had like to get you guys into
topic that's really important for the
rest of the smashing it gives you the
freedom to not be stuck in this
classroom or in tennessee com
we're going to go ahead
gets you started on virtuous jeans here
download a virtual machine
so is this file is gonna be a its
entire operating system inside of a
window for you
you can take that file once you've if
you shut down that
computer in quotes
in turn off you can copy that file
anywhere else
and returning for computer and it will
look like entire computer inside of that
few of the thumb drive
or i have a
usb drive here
you can just take that
but that file on the drive there take it
with you take it to see
and that computer follows you around
for example if you have a whole bunch of
desktops that you're working on
ownership
yet they're not network together you can
take a usb drive with you and on that
usb drive can be your entire work
environment
here on prime
and everything will go with you
to get to it
we need to go
if you go to the research tools website
so all of you hopefully a bookmark this
or have it handy
he'd tone to procreate and you are wrong
this time not gonna bother to make it
pretty
this link for a cure
tiny you are l dot com slash
three and g_ t t geez why
remember more
i will get you write to that
the research
to be honest i haven't done that
alarmist virtual machine stuff
in the past work had to go into more
than a basic soup for you guys i'm
starting to learn some of the better
tricks like how to make a smaller
virtual machine
but i'm not very good at yet so or
images pretty large
read only four gigabyte final
if you scroll down i don't have a nice
link for it yet
right near the bottom
there is a link called virtual dash
machines
click on that
and
the semester i'm gonna be uploading new
virtual machines i'm i have to delete
the old ones eventually because there's
only so much to space on the server
and see if you add up
quickly if you have a lot of them
if you look here
they'll be named with uh... year
the month
and the day
for the directory so that you can figure
out which one you got which once knew
and i'll try to get about
in also named the files
that timestamp
beverage machine so that
you can look at the when you've got see
if if there's a newer one
and i want to download
these two files
there's a pmd katie and i_b_m_ acts
one of them is really big forgive my
feeling is really small two point eight
k
download those two files
as a gestures putting money that's tough
for now
treat these files us
disposable
if you don't like him
fully jump-started and if they blow up
on you and some extras up
these are the files you can glean served
over
but also remember when you're inside
that virtual machine if you start doing
important work for your classes
porphyria tls
back that day tab somewhere else to you
because of virtual machine is easy to
kill and it kills everything very fast
doing one
forty like file
goes like snap
and it's all gone
make sure you back things up
for our work through more strategy
throughout the semester on backing up
threads are telling that most see our
network does with
fifteen or so people all downloading
four gigabytes thing
when you're using a web browser to get
files that are binary
the safest thing i always do
is to right-click rather than left click
and two
save link has
on windows that you can also hold on the
option ki
and i will just merely download the file
without trying to view it
you don't want to view the file that you
view them
what you see won't be that helpful
you're gonna see binary data from
the actual with whom she married and she
did
inside the configuration file
disabling tabs
warner wills upstairs stressing out
watching the network
i see
a little bit of progress here he called
on thirteen minutes
twenty minutes
so go ahead people in that going
i will show you some of the basics will
run through it once
give it a go or if you guys are like if
you have questions from last lecture if
you want to see some examples one
through again or ask ryan to commence
now will be a great time when the
network is complete
clobber the entire building is complete
screaming in agony
because they don't know why everything
is going slow
for them to you
so if you guys have any questions on the
command line
using that
units manned
program to get man pages or getting help
from tools to fax dash help
feel free to show them out for a foot in
the aristide if you've made it into the
ir c channel
if he could never do they don't actually
older
are all those
maybe fever from gene
they should be
what you were walking into called
research tools with a virtual machine
you just didn't know it
so it sitting on the server somewhere
else but that server actually hosts
quite a number of virtual machines
so it's actually serving data up to you
cape cod and talking ships it's doing
stuff for the a_t_ gene
there's little computers on their
vehicle virtual machines there are
taking care of stuff
we've got a very similar virtual machine
running on that
when you do it here
you'll have more
because it installed a graphical
interface
this image is about four gigabytes
the other image i think is currently
under gigabyte so we don't have all the
graphical tools installed on that one so
they'll be more
on which again
the question
i'll go ahead and give you guys
run-through if there's any more
questions
as we go through if i use it to me and i
haven't told you protective will
probably do a lot of
by accident
don't hesitate to shout out questions
let's jump in just take a quick look at
the virtual she now show you saying it
up
when it gets down on your machine
them all went through with all of you
guys
so what i've done
is i'd create a folder
and his name it with the virtual machine
to make life easier
i've run it once
so ignore all sexual junk
screen or temporary files in there that
you know
they don't care about
but there's a tool called vmware player
and if you're finishing
yeah you're using a non secom machine
very lucky doesn't have the m were
player on it
if u
go to the
in just two oh four vmware player you
should be able to download a free player
right away and do the same thing
so five double click on this
it's already got my virtual machine load
up in here but if i hadn't done that
i'm missing skip this version
i to be a_t_t_ managers the software
here
if i try to do the update version
it's not gonna let me simon skip that
awesome to do it
which of you if you go under file he'll
say open a virtual machine
you'll navigate to wherever to machinist
and it's going to show you if if if
those two thousand downloading treat
them as one
virtual machine they go together as a
pair
you'll select that
and hit open
lotte put up a display like this where
you can see
the play virtual machine
blank break here's a quick link to start
up
at edit virtual machines that it's
savannah walking through the summer to
come back to have to it
to tweak your virtual machine a little
bit
and still perfecting why do you
here you can control how much of
resources from your computer you're
going to get to this little virtual
machine
you can get it
a lot
or even given nothing and you can
actually give it more resources than you
have to get yourself in trouble
for example here with memory i've
decided one gigabyte so thats and twenty
four megabytes
let me go to thirty two gigabytes
as they have to create virtual ram on
the desk it's going to go really slow
and you can get rolling about processors
so here i give it gigabyte avram and
the effectively to processors
i believe these computers have
four courses so you can get it
up to four i would suggest not getting
it all of your processing power
this wall out have up to twenty gigabyte
disk to get going
and there's a lot of other printers that
we can go through
later on
but he wanted to go down to is
display
this is the one is the most important
thing set that i haven't done in this
virtual machine yet disks of time
and that's
turn-on accelerate three-d_ graphics
we haven't done much graphics yet but
there are few programs that you'll run
my caloric
if you don't have it sorry three
graphics turned on
over under really slow
so anything it's actually a three-d_
program
pop a hard time
a few that would uh... your
how we have an apply button storms to
hit ok
and they go ahead and launch the
personal xin
which is also called play
yet there's no magic a way to get more
resources so
what you can allocating staying if
you've got a lot of virtual change on a
run
you know one of the controller two
course
there maybe some other ways to improve
how well it runs
to let them all play together nicely
for now you typically you know we learn
one or two virtual machines at the time
there are really busy tools that
like the enterprise version of your own
upstairs which is
vmware
yes acts
and that gives you really
fine-grained control for a lot of
virtual machines
we'd ever have servers that can run
twenty thirty virtual machines
so those virtual machines are doing very
little
if you try run a whole bunch of doing a
lot
fight with each other
inside the virtual machine you often get
a pop up like this about updates to
vmware tools so special schools they
coincide with this program the talk
outside
what we have here is uh... all
terminology problems that can get
confusing as you have host
and guest in the classroom here this is
going to be when does this is what you
sit down
on so windows seven in our case
and the gas
is the personal machine
this is your piano virtual
machine
their software the runs here this is the
vmware player
and in our case where the running you go
into an x
inside it
there's operating system which dorm i
could take over entire machine has
special drivers that make you talked
more effectively with vmware
and that pop up you're seeing in front
of me
that i've got right there where it says
here were tools for one x virginity
point four point four
it this is a driver that runs
on the went to an extent lets it talk
more effectively with
what's going on when decides that is to
know if i shudder
most of the software you're on
in the virtual machine really have no
idea goes on a virtual machine
in fact if you're a python code
that python code will have no idea at
this in all special containers
itil happy happy indicates that a formal
computer
which is that the wonder of virtual
machines one works a lot
it does have a virtual software is good
enough for now so i'm gonna save
remind me later
and hopefully the next time i give you
guys a virtual machine i will go up to
get right before e
and what i've done here is
in setting it up by using account that
was my own
but i've created our research tools
account
that you all have the password to you
it's an administrator
anderson on something if you have a
machine on the network
don't do that shared passwords are
really bad idea
in class for a new uses for
just getting started and what you do
with a virtual machine normally used you
download it
in the change the password
you mean you can't believe that account
to create an account with your username
and password for you is completely
different than what's here is if you
keep a machine running with this
and you've been around
and means to anybody who knows others
prefer machine knows that password
and very bad things that happen
but in this case you have when you get
the virtual machine
this is the password that you're going
to have it's uh... xmission point
party for research tools
two thousand eleven bme
so whenever i distribute the virtual
machine for this class
the username is getting research tools
and the password is going to be that's
in the future will go through
how to create users
sukru yourself for username
and you can go and delete this user
and that if you want to give the virtual
machine to someone else you can go
career recreate this account very easily
and the files to someone else if you've
made a special virtual machines all set
up for some particular cast
you can share that with other people
so unlike before we had to use party to
login
this is the like you're sitting at the
console and as long as by mouse is in
that window
because if i'm typing on my computer so
i can then type
the escalation point party
two thousand eleven
and hit login
that's going to book different then we
walked into the server because were
walking into a graphical interface much
like windows
so things are going to start looking a
little bit different and we can actually
uh...
pretty much full screen
it'll feel weird this'll this replied
the windows stuff away from us
and were in a completely different
operating system
and it has
different ways of interacting that are
similar to when there is
but defer enough of in a trip you up
there's a couple times in the top labs
right now we're running in an alder
style of the u goin to interface there's
a fancier one that requires three
graphics that i haven't quite figured
out how to enable
so it'll look fancier more windows seven
like
if i could figure out how to turn that
on its called unity
but inside here i've pre-installed a
fairly large bid of software to get you
guys going
so that
the first thing you are doing is
learning how to install software to be
able to just get going
out also you will that
you be able to do things like open up a
calculator
for exciting
open up attacked senator
so will be going into can you email us
attacks there will probably
it's very similar to our mac o_s_ and
windows where top left corner if you
wanna kill something you can
collects that goes way
and if you want it
theater face to look very much like what
we had before
conservative about going to under excess
serious
there is a terminal
at least here i know how to make the
point figure
so now you can do those screens we
before for example we can do a p w d
and we're now in home research tools
we can make her
make a directory called past
victor test
t_v_ and contest
together peter the d_n_c_ when our
directory
we can do a long-lasting
and see that there's nothing but
document dot dot
directory is is in there
thinks he told her to go home
now there's a a fair bit more going on
with what's in your folder so it set up
to be f
desktop environment so if you
won a load up your entire music album
into uh...
folder it's also up for that
were intrigued this is a work which you
have an out
or how to play all the fun stuff with
music and what not
the way we want to die
but if you do in
ls dash away in this mission
you're gonna see a whole lot of extra
stuff running around here
don't worry about too much of it
all the configuration information
for the windows winnowing interface and
all devices
cleared her armored
there's lots of it
they're called dot files
that are hiding around taking care pings
for you
derwin doing interface that is being
used as called known
c_n_n_ all and he
and you'll be seeing some of that don't
worry too much about the interface i
think you'll be able to that
after a few minutes guess what you need
to find where
and you get comfortable pretty quickly
switching between windows and unix
about too much worry
how are you guys doing on the downloads
sexy about a third of the way through
yes
i'd used bbm our system itself to treat
it
so what i did as i downloaded and
installed first for even to
and
random vmware player i believe you can
view vmware player
you cannot quite believe create one
so you can see creating a virtual
machine and if you have the install disk
for your operating system
you can put that together as a physical
disk in or if it's a file that you
download
life robotics it'll be uh...
equal one of the cd was called higher so
so the one big file you install from
he'll tell which file to install home it
will do that
operations install as if you're on the
console installing it
inside that little window
we can go to that later in the class
so you guys can create your own virtual
machines if you need something different
there's lots of different types of links
if you have a favorite ones that switch
whoever finished one
anne garrels has to go faster sam
i think it is your classes will try to
have uh...
some other strategy for getting a bit
images will work best for the past
ready to go
before class
so all thats going
i'm gonna show you what it's like to
start up i thought this is the
programming which were actually the
spend most of our time on
in this class
every new tool called i'd pipeline
if that will be enhanced version of pi
pond
so that's the letter high
before python
and i think on is designed to be
more of our and hard work and barman
where you can play with stuff as it goes
you can make plots
and
by type i lab after it
i'm a startup
a whole scientific programming
environment it's designed specifically
for science
the first time you run it
i fight on says i'm setting up a whole
bunch of stuff for you
if they keep histories just like the
back sheltered it's gonna let you
keeping history what's going on
scrolled through things and try to keep
track of your environment
click banner
and you can view things by before we did
appear dvd
you can do it al afs
and you can see the
into our test directory things like that
sorry gives you
a lot of what you have in your
more bash shell you can actually runs
for from inside of us
and python normally doesn't give you
that you have to have to have
but shell open to shell type stuff
with regular pipeline
and the weather python self-test combine
them together and it gives you graphing
so we'll get a complete and permanent
where you can actually spend your entire
day
initial terminal doing data processing
allison's
ice-t_ virtual machine starting out this
is pretty exciting
anticipation helps make an exciting
right
it's easy to prepare for the open
pages needing right next to each other
yet to be in a folder they can be
anywhere you want as long as there
next to you
here
that's where they were not there are too
dot on a mac
so you know i'm showed that up there the
vmware player
i had vmware fusion
and that's where i do much for
development
must every part of him where is that
as long as you have the required
personal machine infrastructure
now you can run
comeback inside personal cheaper than
we're candles
youth problems getting clobbered right
now
go ahead
and
rhamat
and into the open
you're getting three minutes getting
closer
and to virtual machines
if you have the virtual machine go ahead
and login
if you can
figure how to do that
you open guitar player
open mister media could open birds or
seen or filed for them
the same thing
and then you have to go navigate
wherever that is top anxious to see if
there yet
and cacophony
and it should
you don't give a configuration that i
walk you through
but i want to have you seen it just hit
play a few when it comes out
uh... where'd you place the files though
need to download both finals there's two
there's to be in detail which is the big
giant or you might see often download
the little bmx configuration file
o_d_s_
if you get a question that says did you
move it or copy etc you copied it
so you quickly
kwai copied it
if you've got to move it probably will
work i'm just not sure
what it's doing for either one will
probably get you going to him tried i
moved it
are suggesting i copied it
but
that's another one if you see the
keyboard took time out
are out warning
just click ok and don't worry about it
and when you get to the vmware tools
installed to save remind me later
being lazy sometimes it's good
and the password for you
these right up there
this is something that
i'm actually post dispatch from the net
it's going to be in the record lectures
this is not a secure password many means
i'm started so slow didn't go and that's
all the basic steps getting set up to
four agents and fun stuff
new in
needs downloaded the imax
the bizarre bmx configuration file
together what page
leader or the same file to finance the
native della two different files
so there's a v andy k this one
go back to the web
and there's the bmx
save that file save link as
anything in the same directory together
thing for
thing
and now hit play
you copied it
and remind me later an ok yes if it's ok
and remind me later that's fine
online
and now go ahead and login
excellence thus looking good
and you have we have c_e_o_ login once
you see that the string on them
uses actually have everybody log until
the next
and one person actually running for once
native appliance
we're winter
networking
dispersal machine is running on this
dust off
figured this is not the research tools
server that we used before
uh... was a totally new place to be
organize your question
yes to see you log into the virtual
machine
any reenact
what looks like a terminal but i throw
us is attached to the current machine
you're not going over the network at all
if you took these computers and unplug
them from the network
this would still work
so you're not talking any computer out
out there
this is running
rate on the stuff out
don't write it what we will be obsolete
lunch until uh... inside the virtual
machine
but for now we're gonna cause free no to
freak out with
even more
people wont in dire c
two more boys
so don't worry about i thought right now
will get that figured out the top for
the next time
so one thing to discover pretty quickly
is this for sure seem to set up for
security
so far walk away too long it was my
password again
units note after pretty quickly every
time you do some baking
to remove the setup files for phone if
you go out to you
applications on the top lots
under accessories
there's a terminal
and unlike buddy were connecting to the
machine that were on so it's
it's gonna show you going to show you
the research tools this is the username
and there is telling you
the host name which is just given to you
that's pretty boring
and if you do you have to print working
directory
you'll see that your home research tools
eventually you'll create a user for
yourself
will be catching up to outside resources
and pulling in files that we need
and then i think that discounters starts
you off as administrator
so on these windows computers you have
permission to do very little
you can't install software you can do
all sorts of stuff
inside its virtual machine
you have pulled control which means you
can destroy it pretty quickly
you can get yourself pretty confused
but you can also be learn how do stuffs
it's okay to make mistakes inside the
virtual machine
if things break
you can delete the virtual machine
download again from the web and start
over
so don't feel bad if in learning how to
use this virtual machine
things go wrong a few times
the main thing is to use those
experiences picked to figure out
yourself
or at somebody
what went wrong
and how do i not do that next time
in the new place for you can try stuff
out without fear of
in the house coming down on you
so i'm actually in a show you all good
things together
ohmic maternal bigger
how did you
a little bit of this administration and
start looking at the bay area
feminist days in the end
and last time i showed you a tool called
so cap
if you type so catch
and it enter it's gonna say act
that's not here
but they need to go out when they see is
that it seems that you might be the
administrator for this computer
actually knows your name is return that
you could install it if you needed it
it's it's how you recommend to run
and that command is rehear so if you do
you
a funny thing called cdu
anywhere
program called apt debt
install soak act
it's going to
go out to the internet
emperor trusted site gets you this
program so you haven't gone out
terrorist getting any viruses
this is software that's pretty
pretty safe to run released to install
and will go through what these tools do
for now we're just gonna take it as this
is how you install something
skinner said please type in your
password fear and we once did
to get access to the system
and since you can assure you could do
that
both type r
research tools password
bang party
two zero one one two p_m_
answer
that's going to go out
and grab the latest version about
software that has available
schedule lot of stuff that
doesn't have to me i think you right now
at the end if we typed so cat
it says hey i'm running you give me a
options that help
i'm here but
i can understand you if you want to
continue to say yes to continue
what happens is it sometimes
if you install software that software
depends on other software you have this
poultry have people working together
answer tell you i need to install these
couple tools
if you'll be able to give me so fast
that works
and if you were to do this
administration on their own
which a lot of people really like to do
you come back about five hours later in
the city figuring out how to install its
tools
is a good lessons
if you take control c
go ahead and type something
for your keyboards working anytime you
see a pass for prompt
if you start seeing characters then your
password stopped
your password shouldn't appearing less
you have to to appear
if your paper charts apparently type
into something a means that
there's something going from bad
you're not doing what you think you dear
sometime this box was the right thing
but go find a ninety person who is
comfortable with that to tell you
whether or not
police are seen your password going
infinite
it's on the road
should be doing
so now we have this ocap program in
there
if we use ocap
and where do a connection i'll teach you
guys later on
what this is all doing
but if we say data
water one
secom dot an h
and then we're going to give a report
number of thirty six thousand
adapts to say i'd like a plus or minus
sign honor
that's gonna put
dal porto stared out which is the consul
you can also send that output to files
two other computers it's really powerful
won't get into too much that
to a vertical bar
and head
vertical bar means sending it to another
program
remus this had program
tilma give us the first time line so it
doesn't just keeps going by it
capris
to brave go ahead and hit enter
that vertical bar is
right above your return key
vehicle down shifts
there should be between backspace in
enter should be a vertical bar
the lessons of pipe
and what you're seeing up here
is data coming up
from our the roof of our building
charlotte aeromar whether sensor splash
i'd g_p_s_ that you have ownership
people on the buildings that would not
for people partnerships
and then
had a program just took the first time
lines and then quit
and so there's a layer from so cap or
try to send us more data
and it's a there's a broken pipe is
unhappy
there's a lot of funny analogies in unix
about pipes in
plumbing and things like that
will see more of those as we go more
walk through some of that's researching
a sense of how these things work but now
you that we've seen
you can look up to live data in this
tool and start working at it
lots of people in trouble tests so
castings
a hot
stares us
a problem that i thought about lunchtime
when you wait
data
logger
and then that there's a some character
right after that
if iran upon the whiteboard
my health tablets
or a big whoop my ones shouldn't have a
live
and if you have a little bar underneath
but the one at the end bijoy of some
fonts if you look really closely up here
data longer with the what the hell
character
has a a bar across the bottom
their elements for interest on a little
half
if you don't want really carefully ones
and alleles for traveling a confusing
demand so cat
faulty purpose relates socket capt
i'm not sure is going to help your whole
life
by the end of semester
that might mean something to you and i
would be helpful thing but right now
it's just called so catch
that's what we have notes
and so any work through things you take
don't seem to figure it out and
eventually
elsewhere means a great now
socket cat
not terribly helpful i would imagine
and cat doesn't have anything to do with
dr
with unix and one x
you're building up little pieces and
those pieces the more peace you have the
more powerful your skills are
certainly out a little piece it's more
than a sign that peace is the whole
combination
uh... powerful tools that are filling
out this library of things that you can
conquer some data
does anyone still stock on the so cat
that had ron
successfully
i see lots of
success
so that's it for today search for class
next week
will be even more into this and will
start using
that text editor if you want to play
with and take a peek
it's called he max
and three pairs so can you email acts
there's many email access there is not
all the same
the one we are going to use his canoe
he max
version in this twenty three that the
version number
this tool has been around since the
nineteen seventies
so we got more powerful
and this is opposed to give ur hear
someone say
d_r_i_
that's a different under and we'll talk
about the eyes box
to finish up
you could probably disclose this is a
couple weeks do with the virtual machine
you can suspend it
and it will just as we freeze the
machine in place
by taking a person of putting a freeze
prey on them they start moving
you can also
shut it down completely so it's almost
like turning off the power
but it's in a little window so your
overall computer will stay on but a
little window
turns off the tickets
that's how it goes down
so the top rate has got
this little button
and here you know what the power icon
are you don't i'd didn't for awhile was
very confused
so this circle with a dash to the top
raise your power options you can do
things like
walks clean eccentric center
you can log out and become a different
user
so suspend hibernate will start the
machine down temporarily relieve come
right back to where you were
for now we're just gonna go ahead and do
a full shut down
good to pay attention to what your
shutting down aren't shutting down
to actual computer
where the power of tax return off
reached running down
virtual machine
and if you're running lights
reversal g_ inside
if you think you're in fullscreen mode
you might not be
and spoke you may actually show up a
whole machine attention not just the
commission
yeah it can be a little we're too
confusing
illiteracy here you can see you go into
a shouting itself often is now powered
down
except for no power has changed
were back to it is
to take a little while he used to that
and but hopefully
the great thing is that you put that on
the usb stick you go home
to another country
go out to sea
it's on a usb stick you copy that file
to a workstation on the ship use a whole
bunch
if you forget that
while on the desk
that's on some of the machine you at
home with the usb stick you still have
it
hasn't gone anywhere you just need a
copy
you can give it to other people on the
ship
if you've got stuck the iraq all set up
for prostitutes are kind of data
for example the weather station here
you could give it to the ship
they could then turned on
change the address is in their
deployment there weather station
and boom you've got a weather station
pricing system
all from little file
yes and i highly recommend that usb
stick you can put the installer for
vmware player out of the windows and one
x and mac
seemed to have everything you need and
be a lock up to almost any machine and
get going